Welcome to Introduction to C++.
My name is Kate Gregory, and I'd like to introduce myself by telling people I've
been using C++ since before Microsoft had a C++ compiler.
That's well over 20 years, and, in that time, I've seen a lot of changes to the
language and to how people use it.
You know if you did a course in college 10 or 20 years where you know somebody
who did, and they told you about it, you might not recognize the C++ I'm going to
show you.
I'm going to teach you the basics you need to write good C++.
It's the most popular general-purpose programming language ever and one that's still
relevant and useful today.
To get started in this module, I'm going to tell you some of the advantages of C++
and why so many developers are using it.
You'll also see what C++ CLI is, what C++ OX is, and start to learn what Modern C++
is, and why it's the way to write C++ this century, and then you'll be ready to start
writing some code.