I'd like to start by giving you an overview of how the course as a whole comes together.
We're going to start with context, why C++, what are all these words and terminologies, so
that you kind of feel you know where you stand, and then get you set up with the tools
that you need in order to follow along in the demos.
Once that's taken care of, you can get into writing some simple applications that
demonstrate the language basics.
You know, like any programming language, C++ lets you declare and work with the variables,
and it's an object-oriented language so you can make objects and define classes, and
you can control the flow of your application, like have a loop, do things over and over,
or check to see if a particular condition holds or not.
The syntax there is just something that we have to cover in order to build larger
applications together.
One of the things that's a little unusual about C++ is the way it actually lets
you extend the language to your own objects and classes, and so we have to talk a
little bit more about operators than we normally would.
Then we can start to talk about templates.
This is really something that sets C++ apart from other languages, and it is also
one of the cornerstones of C++.
It makes your life simpler.
It's not a complicated advanced feature.
It's something that you need to know really from the beginning, and then we have
to talk about Pointers.
A lot of people of scared of pointers, because they were taught Pointers the old-school way.
In Modern C++, the responsibility for memory management is not on the programmer.
There's a powerful Standard Library to help you perform common tasks, so it's all about
power, but not about danger, and understanding Pointers in that context gets you
positioned to really take advantage of what Modern C++ has to offer.