You've probably decided to give C++ a chance.
After all, you're willing to start going through this material with me.
But maybe you're still not a 100% sure that you want to learn it, or maybe even when
you know it, you're not sure if it's the right thing to use for the particular
project that you're taking on.
C++ is a general-purpose language.
It means you can use it for large, big metal applications that are doing number
crunching, you know, simulating the weather on the entire world or controlling
complicated real-time equipment.
You can use it for a web service.
You can use it for a client-based application that runs on your Windows' machine,
and shows people screens, and asks them questions, and puts the answers in the database.
You can use it for a tiny, little hand-held device of some kind, maybe a phone,
maybe something tablet-y, whatever.
Much, much smaller memory space, much, much smaller hard drive than that big
iron-crunching, but the same programming language the whole way.
So across a variety of platforms and across a variety of problem sets, C++ is a
language that's well tuned to all of those.
If you think of some other popular languages, maybe some other languages you know,
often people will describe them and say, "Well that's a great language for writing
a web application.
"That's a great language for writing a text-processing application.
"That's a great language for numerical number crunching."
Terrific.
C++ is a great language for all of those things and one that you can leverage your
knowledge of across a variety of different kinds of projects.
C++ is about speed, about power, about performance.
Where decisions are being made back in the language design level, very often the
question is, "Which way would be faster at run time?" and that's the way it got done.
Another real popular question is, "Which gives the programmer the most control?"
A lot of decisions are left up to the programmer in the language in order that you
can take the way that's faster in your particular case.
You know, whenever you talk about performance, the answer is often, "It depends," and
when a language makes a single choice, then the developer can't adapt to the
circumstances they find themselves in.
In C++, because there's tremendous fine-grain control over what happens, you can
choose the approach that makes your application perform as powerfully as possible,
and C++ is a very popular language.
Microsoft's Visual C++ team went out to do some numbers.
Who's still using Native C++?
And they discovered, Wow, a lot of people are using Native C++.
They went to a number of open-source repositories and just ran the numbers.
How many projects are written in each language?
To their, I've got to say, to their tremendous surprise, the number one language was C++,
and not just from Windows' projects, but across a variety of platforms.
And for college students, that's the language college students are using.
Not just for their assignments, but also for their personal projects.
And when you have a ten-million developer base as C++ does, you have a lot of great
libraries out there.
Libraries that provide general-purpose algorithms, containers, what-not, helpful things,
and specialized libraries that are all about image processing, or internet
transmission, or things that you and I have never even heard of, but someone's
gone and written an open-source C++ library that you can use to make that work simpler.
Leveraging other people's work is obviously another great path to power and
performance, because that's code that you didn't have to write.
People talk a lot about how C++ is the language for speed, and it is, but
that doesn't mean it's the language for just a small, select group of people.
It's an incredibly popular general-purpose language and investing the time
in learning it for one context may often bring you benefits in another context,
and that's why I think it's worth learning.