There's just one problem when you're talking about "Why C++?", and that's the
other side of the question, "Why not C++?"
It's all power, performance, control.
It's popular.
It's general purpose.
Why isn't everybody using it?
Well, you know you may have heard that it's hard.
Mmm…I got to kind of disagree.
Modern C++ is really not hard.
What's probably got you nervous about C++ is that someone else has told you, or
that you remember from a long time ago, are things that really aren't in
Modern C++.
So the first thing about Modern C++ is using the Standard Library.
The Standard Library has a string class in it.
The Standard Library has great collections and smart pointers that take care of
memory management, like you do not have to delete memory that you allocated with NuGet.
And it has File IO, Screen IO, and far too much to list.
The same way if you've done .NET programming, it comes with a library of bits and
pieces.
You've done Java programming; it comes with a library of bits of pieces, and C++
comes with a library of bits of pieces, called the Standard Library.
This isn't something that you get around to later once you're good at it.
This is something you do from the beginning, using these out-of-the-box capabilities
for your string manipulations for your collections to spare you the trouble of
memory management, or pointer arithmetic, or a lot of the stuff that people kind
of get afraid of.
Modern C++ is powerful, but it's still readable, and it's not dangerous.
Managing memory yourself, that's last century C++.
That is not what we're going to be doing.
It's not what is expected of people who are writing ordinary C++ application.
A little bit different if you're writing a library, you just want to write an
application.
You're not going to manage memory, and that means you're not
going get all caught-up in a lot of the dangers of managing your own memory,
pointer arithmetic, those kinds of things.
In fact, when I show Modern C++ to people who know C# or to people who know Java,
what they tend to say with a tremendous amount of surprise is, "Hey, I can read that!"
and they're not expecting it.
We've all heard the joke, or at least those of us who work in C++ have heard the
joke, it's like a bunch of comic book characters swearing at each other, and
we do have a lot of different pieces of punctuation in C++, and they serve
purposes, rather than just using dot for everything.
But when you look at Modern C++, you'll be able to read it, if you know C# or Java.
What's cool is how much faster it is.
Let me just give you one example.
Java and C# both have generics, the idea that you have a list of some things
or a queue of some things, and C++ has them, too.
C++ has templates.
Now generics are resolved at run time.
That means every time your application runs, some number of cycles are going
to be spent figuring out, you know, what type do I use?
What method do I call?
What's going on here?
Templates in C++ are resolved at compile time.
That means those cycles are not spent at run time.
The application's just plain faster, as a result, and those kind of advantages
keep showing up when you're working in C++.
That's why it's the first choice for speed of execution.
So if it's readable, it's not complicated, doesn't have to be hard, and is just
flat out faster.
Now you're starting to see why C++ is such a popular language.