So at least for a moment, bear with me that you agree that C++ is a great language
to learn and a great language to use, because it is so general purpose in cross
platform and powerful in performance, and that although you've heard it's hard,
you're prepared to believe that Modern C++ is maybe not hard.
Now if you already know C# or Java or some other language featuring brace
brackets and semicolons, you may feel like, "Okay, I can do this.
"I'm going to learn this hard thing," even though I've told you it's not real hard.
But, surely, someone who doesn't know a programming language already should never
start with something as terrifying as C++.
Well, I disagree.
I think C++ is a fine first language.
When I started to learn to program, we had less languages to choose from.
But even 20 years ago when I had been doing C++ for while, it was still
a really popular first programming language.
Generations of people learned C++ and got out in the world and turned into
decent programmers, whether they ended up working long-term in C++ or not.
It's certainly true that compared to the kind of C++ that was being taught 20 years
ago, C# and Java are way easier.
But you know, that's like comparing a car to like a wood-fired steam engine or
something, and thinking that that's saying anything about cars versus trains.
Modern C++ is not too hard for beginners.
Many of the things that used to have to be done right at the beginning around
memory management, and pointer arithmetic, and doing a whole lot of stuff by hand,
that's just not part of Modern C++.
You have a library that helps you, the same as those other languages have libraries
that help you, and you have some very powerful constricts to keep you safe while
you're having high-performance application.
So even if you don't know another programming language, why not get started with C++?
Now in this material, I'm not going to be covering basic programming concepts,
like what is a loop and why are things sometimes true and sometimes false, but
you don't need to feel that, "Oh, I can't learn C++ because I don't know some other
language."
It's fine if this is the first language that you take on.
If you do happen to know C# or Java, then you're going to learn C++ pretty
quickly, because you're going to recognize a lot and say, "Oh, that's just like what already knew!"
Now there are some things that are different, so don't get too overconfident.
If you know old school C++, if you're one of those people who says, "Well, you what?
"I've worked with this 10 years ago and now I have to come back to it," you may actually
have a tougher time, because you're going to have to unlearn some things that were
beaten into you that you really don't need to worry about so much anymore and
you can lax a little and trust a little, and I will show you how it's really
all going to be okay.
If you don't know any programming languages yet, welcome aboard.
You're going to have to look a little elsewhere for sort of concepts of programming
languages, but you don't need to already know C or C# or Java in order to grasp
the concept of C++.
You can learn it as your first language.