I'd like to clear up a little nomenclature before we dig into the actual
heavy-duty details of syntax, and library, and all of that.
You may have heard of C++/CLI, and to be honest, people sometimes
mis-abbreviate this or they put dots in there.
If you've heard C++ and CL something together, this is probably what they were
trying to remember.
You know, there are a number of languages that are sort of based on C++.
After all, there's this huge pool of developers that already know the syntax,
so you say, "My language has the same syntax as C++, except for this one little
thing," and very often, these variants will work with libraries that already
out there and with tools that are already out there, maybe with a little bit
of extension or modification.
And this is a powerful way to bring new capabilities to that pool of C++ developers.
And C++/CLI is one of those variants, and it makes managed code.
So once upon a time, you know, before there was a .NET framework, before there was
Java, there was C++, and it compiled to machine code on the machine that you
were building on.
Nowadays, we call that native code, because we need to distinguish that native code
that actually runs directly on the metal from code that runs against some kind of a
run time, whether it's a Java run time, or C#.NET framework run time, or you're
writing in DB.NET and running against the .NET frameworks run time.
Normal ordinary C++ produces native code, and Microsoft has compilers that
come in Visual Studio that make native code.
But it also has a set of tools inside Visual Studio that can make managed code
from C++ source code.
Managed code that can be easily called from C#, or DB, or any other kind of
managed code you have kicking around.
It does this with some extensions to the language itself, so it's not C++, it's
C++/CLI, because it's a little different, has a few extra key words in it,
a few extra pieces of punctuation.
And this is a fantastic way to take a native library that was maybe written
a long time ago, and wrap it up, put a wrapper around it to make it easy to
call from .NET code.
I'm not going to cover C++/CLI at all.
If you learn C++, then you basically know C++/CLI, as well.
You just need to learn the few extra little pieces of punctuation and key
words, and you're good to go, and you'll be in a position to write those
wrappers.
But we are not going to have any C++/CLI content.
We're all about native code.