Something else you may have heard or read is C++0x.
In order to understand what that is, we need to sort of back up a little
bit to who owns C++.
The answer is kind of nobody.
No one person sat down and invented it.
Bjarne, the father of C++, and a number of different compiler venders make C++ compilers,
but the owners of those compilers can't arbitrarily decide to change the language.
So, take a language like Visual Basic, which eventually became Visual Basic .NET,
that's just a language that Microsoft developed and owns, and if they want to add a
key word to it, they just add a key word to it.
C++ isn't like that.
It's got a standard that says, "Here are the key words in this language," and
the standard library that I mentioned is part of the standard.
So there's a standards committee, and they get together and decide whether
or not to add a key word or a piece of punctuation.
They decide whether or not to add some capabilities to the library.
The current version, before C++0x, was technically C++03, but most
people called it C++98, because 03 was just a little kind of tweaky update.
And to be honest, most people just called it C++ and didn't have any idea
what the year was from.
Back when the 03 version finished, there were people saying, "Okay, let's
get going on the next one.
"It's going to be 0 something; we don't know what.
"It'll be some time before 2009," and right away, the joke was, "Boy,
"I hope X doesn't need to be a hexadecimal digit!" now which, of course,
it did.
Eventually, it'll probably be ll or 12.
It's pretty much done now, has to go through some hoops, and it'll end
up being C++11 or C++12.
Of course, we'll just call it C++.
There's some new functionality added, some new key words, some new
punctuation, and a lot of very cool stuff in the library, and we'll just
use it, and we won't really remember a time when that wasn't there.
You know, I remember a time when certain key words weren't in C++, but
I don't go around saying, "Oh, hmm…oh, you're using that key word.
"Gees, that was only added in 1998.
"That's very modern of you," and it'll be the same with these C++0x key words.
They'll just be normal.
They'll just be what C++ had in them.
Now the standards committee is an interesting mix of people from compiler
vendors; people who just care about the language; people who use the language a lot;
people from academia; and so on.
And the compiler vendors, it's all been a completely open and transparent process.
When they could see, yes, we all agree on this, and no matter how long the whole
standard gets to put together, one particular aspect is going to be adopted
for sure and started to put that capability into the compilers.
So Visual Studio 2010, which has already been released, supports all of the library
changes in C++0x, and almost all of the language changes.
So if you're using Visual Studio 2010, including the Express Edition, you can
just work with C++0x features that I'm going to show you in this course, and
never particularly know whether they're added just now or whether they're from
ten years ago, or twenty years ago, or whatever.
Just to be on the safe side, when I show you something that's from C++0x, I
will point it out so that if you have some C++ experience from the past,
you say, "Wait, I don't think that's a key word," you'll get a little bit of
a reminder that's it's a new key word, so that you don't feel that something
strange is happened when you weren't looking.