Are you ready to write some code?
I've shown you that C++ is a powerful language that's used by ten million developers
and more, and it's rich in libraries and sample code, works across a variety of
platforms, and gives you tremendous performance.
That's what it's all about.
Sure, you may have heard that it's a difficult language, but it doesn't have to be,
especially, if you write Modern C++.
It's clean. It's simple, and it lets the Standard Library do a lot of the work.
Things that you think are too different to do by hand, you probably don't have to do by hand.
Things that you think are hard to read if you do it 1990 C++ way, don't have to be
hard to read at all, if you do it the Modern C++ way.
That's what I'm going to focus on and show you, and you're going to be productive
from the very beginning using C++.